<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tasmota on Ian Duffy</title>
    <link>http://ianduffy.ie/categories/tasmota/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tasmota on Ian Duffy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ianduffy.ie/categories/tasmota/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exposing my desk to Home Assistant</title>
      <link>http://ianduffy.ie/2022/07/11/exposing-my-desk-to-home-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ianduffy.ie/2022/07/11/exposing-my-desk-to-home-assistant/</guid>
      <description>I have a sit/stand desk. It has two buttons for control, one goes up, the other goes down. It connects to a control box via an RJ45 plug.
I wanted to connect the desk to Home Assistant so that I could use Alexa to move the desk up and down, to go to specific height percentages, and to connect to automations e.g. Via the Home Assistant OSX application Home Assistant is made aware if my webcam is on/off, I can use a state change to on to automatically make the desk go up to encourage me to stand during meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining smart switches and smart lights</title>
      <link>http://ianduffy.ie/2022/06/27/combining-smart-switches-and-smart-lights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ianduffy.ie/2022/06/27/combining-smart-switches-and-smart-lights/</guid>
      <description>Lighting is core to any smart home system. The systems attempt to make it as accessible as possible; there shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a need to search for a light switch when entering a walkway a motion sensor should take care of it, there shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a need to have to get out of bed to switch out the light before going to sleep, there shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a need to run around every room before leaving the house to ensure lights are off and there shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a need to manually turn on and off your outdoor lights every night.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
