<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Serverless on Ian Duffy</title>
    <link>http://ianduffy.ie/categories/serverless/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Serverless on Ian Duffy</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://ianduffy.ie/categories/serverless/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Keeping the Wife Happy: Building a Modern Website with Astro and TinaCMS</title>
      <link>http://ianduffy.ie/2024/08/17/keeping-the-wife-happy-building-a-modern-website-with-astro-and-tinacms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://ianduffy.ie/2024/08/17/keeping-the-wife-happy-building-a-modern-website-with-astro-and-tinacms/</guid>
      <description>When my wife, Ciara, told me she wanted to start a blog, my initial reaction was, “Oh no, here we go!” I knew setting up a website could quickly become complicated, expensive, and require ongoing maintenance—something I&amp;rsquo;d rather avoid. So, what&amp;rsquo;s a guy to do?&#xA;The Classic Options: WordPress or Static Sites? The first thing that came to mind was WordPress. It’s user-friendly, which would make it easy for Ciara to manage content on her own.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing access to multiple AWS Accounts with OpenID</title>
      <link>http://ianduffy.ie/2018/12/15/managing-access-to-multiple-aws-accounts-with-openid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 14:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://ianduffy.ie/2018/12/15/managing-access-to-multiple-aws-accounts-with-openid/</guid>
      <description>Many organisations look towards a multiple account strategy with Amazon Web Services (AWS) to provide administrative isolation between workloads, limited visibility and discoverability of workloads, isolation to minimize blast radius, management of AWS limits and cost categorisation. However, this comes at a large complexity cost, specifically around Identity Access Management (IAM).&#xA;Starting off with a single AWS account, and using a handful of IAM users and groups for access management, is usually the norm.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
