<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>smart home on Ian Duffy</title>
    <link>http://ianduffy.ie/categories/smart-home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in smart home on Ian Duffy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ianduffy.ie/categories/smart-home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Combining smart switches and smart lights</title>
      <link>http://ianduffy.ie/2022/06/27/combining-smart-switches-and-smart-lights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ianduffy.ie/2022/06/27/combining-smart-switches-and-smart-lights/</guid>
      <description>Lighting is core to any smart home system. The systems attempt to make it as accessible as possible; there shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a need to search for a light switch when entering a walkway a motion sensor should take care of it, there shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a need to have to get out of bed to switch out the light before going to sleep, there shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a need to run around every room before leaving the house to ensure lights are off and there shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a need to manually turn on and off your outdoor lights every night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live TV distribution and centralised recording</title>
      <link>http://ianduffy.ie/2022/06/27/live-tv-distribution-and-centralised-recording/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ianduffy.ie/2022/06/27/live-tv-distribution-and-centralised-recording/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: The following setup is for personal distribution purposes only. If you have a TV tuner a TV license must be held.
Live TV isn&amp;rsquo;t often used in my household as most of the content we consume is via streaming services (Netflix, Disney+, Amazon Prime). I wanted a selection of Live TV to be available for those moments when we aren&amp;rsquo;t interested in committing to a 2 hour movie, season long show, or RTE were doing their yearly live broadcast of the late late Toy Show and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to rely on their ever failing web player.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
